sdl.com 2014-07-27

# Privacy Policy | SDL

  * In using our websites, SDL will ensure your privacy is protected. We will not sell your personal information and will only use it for internal purposes.
  * We place various cookies on your browser enabling us to understand how you are using our websites and to learn how we can provide you with better experiences and offers that align with your needs. Some of the cookies are for third parties that help us advertise and measure the impact of our advertising. Cookies are important to the proper functioning of a site and rejecting them will negatively affect your web experience. Should you nonetheless decide to reject cookies please refer to our Cookie Policy page.

This privacy policy explains how SDL plc uses and protects the data provided to or collected through the SDL websites. The objective is to provide our visitors with a quality online experience whilst safeguarding your privacy. 

By registering onto our website and providing certain information about yourself, SDL can use this information to provide a better experience to you. In using our websites, SDL will ensure your privacy is protected.

* * *

You are in control of the personal information you provide to SDL and you can: 

  * Ask for a copy of your personal information 
  * Ask for personal information to be corrected or updated
  * Ask to remove your personal information from our records 

The aim of our Privacy Policy is to explain the following: 

  1. The type of information SDL collects from you and what this information is used for 
  2. How this information is protected

When you access SDL websites, some information is automatically collected as specified below. No other information is collected through the SDL websites unless you deliberately decide to send it to us (e.g., by submitting a completed contact form), which is also specified below. 

“Automatically Collected Information” means the following categories and specific information: 

  * “Client Information”: the Internet domain, registered company (if applicable), GeoIP information, and IP address of the computer you are using. 
  * “Essential Technical Information”: identification of the page or service you are requesting, type of browser and operating system you are using; and the date and time of access. 
  * “Nonessential Technical Information”: the Internet address of the web site from which you linked directly to our web site, and the "Cookie Information" described below. Please read our Cookie policy for more information. 

“Optional Information” includes the following information: 

  * When responding to online forms or other questions or comment in a blog: any information entered into these forms, questions or blog comment fields. 
  * When you register an account on the SDL websites: your name, e-mail address, and any additional information you provide as part of your registration. 

This is all classified as personal information under applicable privacy and data protection laws. 

When you purchase a product or service, SDL will collect credit card information for invoicing purposes. This information is processed on behalf of SDL by a third party payment services provider. That provider and SDL use security techniques, including encryption and secure servers to protect you against unauthorised access. 

 **SDL Trados Studio Experience**

In the event that SDL customers or users join the online SDL Trados Experience Program which is an information system to help SDL improve upon the quality and performance of the SDL Trados Software, SDL will not collect the following information from you: 

  * Any content you process, neither in the source nor target languages with which you work 
  * Any content from your translation memories or terminology databases 
  * Your name, address or any other personally identifiable information

SDL uses the information to provide, maintain, protect and improve the services it provides. We use this information to provide you with content tailored to your specific needs. 

When you contact SDL, we may keep a record of your communication to help resolve any issues that you may have. We may use your email address that you provide to inform you about our services but we will only do this if you consent to receiving updated information about our services.

SDL also uses information collected from cookies and other technologies such as Google Analytics to improve your user experience and the general quality of our services. The collected information is used to learn about the usage patterns of visitors to our websites by collecting information about which individual webpages were visited, how long users visited the website, which websites referred the most visitors, general geographic location of visitors and other similar anonymous statistics. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within SDL websites to visitors whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area. 

In order to distinguish one visit from another, Google Analytics may create several tracking cookies on a visitor’s computer which will expire after two years have passed since the initial visit.

SDL strives to protect your personal information to the highest level, for example by encrypting sensitive data using SSL. 

SDL reviews the information it collects, stores and processes and implements physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems.

SDL restricts your personal information provided to its employees, contractors and agents who have a need to know that information in order to process it for SDL. Each employee, contractors or agent contractually obligated by SDL to keep the information received strictly confidential and will face severe penalties if they breach this obligation. 

SDL ensures that its Privacy Policy is in compliance with all applicable privacy laws and regulations. 

SDL complies with the US - EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US - Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set by the U.S Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland and SDL has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program and to view SDL’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>

Please note that our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. This will not change your rights under this Privacy Policy without your express consent. 

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about the Privacy Policy, please contact us as follows 

FAO: Rebecca Thompson-Addo (Legal Team)   
SDL plc   
Globe House   
Clivemont Road   
Maidenhead   
SL6 7DY   
TEL: + 44 (0) 1628 760610   
Fax: +44 (0) 1628 760611   
Or by email at: tpsales@sdl.com 

Last updated: April 2014
